CATHOLICS AGAINST CAPITAL PUNISHMENT RECORDS (APAP321) 1972-2010
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records 1972-2010
nam_apap321
0.80
Catholics Against Capital Punishment
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY
The Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records is a small collection that contains several articles, statements, and pamphlets making a case against the death penalty from a Catholic standpoint.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Frank McNeirney donated the Catholics Against Capital Punishment Records in 2010 to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Historical Note
Francis (Frank) McNeirney and his wife Ellen founded Catholics Against Capital Punishment (CACP) in 1992 in Bethesda, Maryland. The organization's goal was to take a public pro-life stance against the death penalty using Catholicism as a basis for its views, and encourage others with similar mind-sets to support or join the cause. In late 2011 founder Frank McNeirney passed away, and his wife decided to retire from the organization. She passed the organization's website domain on to a sister organization, Catholic Mobilizing Network, for its use, so that supporters of CACP could continue their outreach.
Scope and Content Information
This collection contains papers related to the Catholics Against Capital Punishment (CACP) cause, most notably articles and statements regarding the death penalty from a Catholic perspective. Some booklets and pamphlets from conferences and other organizations are included as well. A large part of the collection consists of articles and statements organized by the state of origin. The District of Columbia is included along with 44 states; Delaware, Hawaii, Oklahoma, Tennessee, Vermont, and Wyoming are missing. There are several official statements released or sanctioned by the United States Conference of Catholic Bishops, referred to as U.S.C.C.B. for convenience. One compact disk is included in the collection that accompanies the booklet Death Penalty Resources for Communities of Faith.
The archivist transferred one monograph: Beyond the Death Penalty written by Joe Holland and D. Michael McCarron to the book division of Special Collections. This will be cataloged and included at a later date in the University Library Catalog.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged alphabetically. There are no series.
Subject and Genre Headings
Social Activists and Public Advocates; Death Penalty; Catholics Against Capital Punishment; Catholic Church. United States Conference of Catholic Bishops; Capital punishment--Religious aspects--Baptists, [Catholic Church, etc.]; Articles; Pamphlets
Container List
- Articles and Statements-Alabama, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Articles and Statements-Alaska, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Articles and Statements-Arizona, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Articles and Statements-Arkansas, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Articles and Statements-California, 1985; 1992-1993; 1999; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Articles and Statements-Colorado, 1994; 1997; 2002; 2005; 2009 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Articles and Statements-Connecticut, 1990; 1998-1999; 2005; 2009 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Articles and Statements-District of Columbia, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Articles and Statements-Florida, 1972-1979; 1983-1984; 1990-1997; 2009 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Articles and Statements-Georgia, 1992; 2008 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Articles and Statements-Idaho, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Articles and Statements-Illinois, 1983; 1988; 1994-1996; 1998-1999; 2002 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Articles and Statements-Indiana, 1986; 1994; 1996; 1998-1999; 2009 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Articles and Statements-Iowa, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Articles and Statements-Kansas, 1994; 1998; 2002; 2009-2010 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Articles and Statements-Kentucky, 1984; 1996; 2007; Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Articles and Statements-Louisiana, 1992; 1994; 1996 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Articles and Statements-Maine, 1996; Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Articles and Statements-Maryland, 1993; 1996-1998; 2005; 2008-2009; Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Articles and Statements-Massachusetts, 1997; 1999; 2001; 2004; 2007 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Articles and Statements-Michigan, 1985-1986; 1993; 1999 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Articles and Statements-Minnesota, 1993; 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Articles and Statements-Mississippi, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Articles and Statements-Missouri, 1994; 2006; 2010 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Articles and Statements-Montana, 1995; 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Articles and Statements-Nebraska, 1994; 1996; 2010; Undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Articles and Statements-Nevada, 1996; 1998 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Articles and Statements-New Hampshire, 2007-2010 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Articles and Statements-New Jersey, 1989; 1993; 1996-1999; 2004-2005; 2007 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Articles and Statements-New Mexico, 1996; 1998-1999; 2000; 2010 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Articles and Statements-New York, 1994-1996; 1999; 2002-2003; 2005; 2007 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Articles and Statements-North Carolina, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Articles and Statements-North Dakota, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Articles and Statements-Ohio, 1987; 1996; 2009 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Articles and Statements-Oregon, 1996; 2009 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Articles and Statements-Pennsylvania, 1989; 1995-1996; 2000-2001; 2007 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Articles and Statements-Rhode Island, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Articles and Statements-South Carolina, 1992; 1998 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Articles and Statements-South Dakota, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Articles and Statements-Texas, 1979; 1984-1985; 1992-1999; 2000-2008 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Articles and Statements-Utah, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Articles and Statements-Virginia, 1988; 1993; 2001; 2007; 2009 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Articles and Statements-Washington State, 1992; 1998; 2007; 2009 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Articles and Statements-West Virginia, 1980; 1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Articles and Statements-Wisconsin, 1987; 1993; 1995 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- General Pamphlets, Articles, and Statements Regarding Catholic Views on the Death Penalty, 1992-1995; 1997-1998; 2000-2005; Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Testimony and Letters to the U.S. Senate, House of Representatives, and the Supreme Court issued with the support of the U.S.C.C.B., 1989; 1994; 2001 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- U.S.C.C.B. Official Statements, 1978; 1980; 1994-1990; 2000-2005 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Vatican Officials' Statements, 1991; 1996-1999; 2001; 2005-2010 (Box 3, Folder 2)